

MICHAL MARSZALEK

Junior Software Developer

@ mw.marszalek@outlook.com

J +44-7868-272-531

■ Glasgow, Scotland

in /mwmarszalek

/mwmarszalek

Dev Portfolio

SKILLS

Python JavaScript Java

Node.js React.js Spring

MongoDB PostgreSQL

HTML CSS REST API

Bootstrap Flask Mocha

Cypress Jest unittest

TDD

OOP

LEARNING

Agile

C# .Net Core Docker

TOOLS

Git

Azure Data Studio Postman

VSCode IntellliJ IDEA

Excel PowerBi Insomnia

Postico

Anaconda Slack ZSH

Chrome GitHub Figma

Draw.io MongoDB Compass

LANGUAGES

English: Proficient / C2

Polish: Native

ABOUT ME

I am a Junior Software Developer with a background in Social Statistics. Prior to transitioning into coding, I worked as a Technical Coordinator & Team Leader in the automotive industry where I managed and presented data for R&D departments using Excel with VBA and PowerBI. I have completed multiple bootcamps and a 16-week intensive Professional Software Development Course at CodeClan. I have very good work discipline which I gained from being a marathon runner. I am excited to continue my journey as a software developer and contribute to innovative projects.

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

Professional Software Development Course | Codeclan

11 2022 - 03 2023

Glasgow, Scotland

- 16 week intensive SQA accredited course teaching the fundamentals of software development across a range of languages and frameworks, using Agile methodologies, TDD and OOP to build full-stack applications. Over 800 hours of instructor-led coding, pair programming and group project experience
- Skills: Python HTML CSS PostgreSQL Javascript React Express MongoDB Java Spring GIT RESTful workflow Mocha, Jest, Cypress, unittest

PROJECTS

ii 14 days

- Macros is a full-stack calorie tracking app that enables users to set nutrition goals and track their daily food/macro stats over time.
- I was solely responsible for designing and coding the entire multi-step onboarding process, ensuring that new users were properly saved to the database.
- I worked on connecting the app to the API and integrating the back-end with the front-end.
- I contributed to API data filtering functionality and the implementation of the responsive UI design using Bootstrap.
- Stack: JavaScript React Java Spring Boot PostgreSQL• Bootstrap HTML CSS

BeeCareful | 🖸 🕨 Demo

ii 14 days

- Beecareful is a full-stack app designed for beehive management. It enables users to track daily inspections, hive health, bee colonies, and weather using an external API.
- I was solely responsible for connecting to external weather API and making the containing component conditionally render different styles based on temperature/wind data.
- Solely responsible for the app component structure and overall design
- Greatly contributed to the communication between front-end and back-end
- Stack: JavaScript React Express MongoDB HTML CSS

Earth Trekker | 🗘 🔼 Demo

- **=** 5 days
- Earth Trekker is full-stack CRUD app developed solo over 5 days in Python with Flask and a PostgreSQL database which allows users to track countries and cities they visited or plan to visit. I drew from my own experience as a seasoned traveller to design the functionality and user interface.
- Stack: Python Flask PostrgeSQL HTML CSS

CAREER

Technical Coordinator | Scottish Leather Group

1 01 2020 - 03 2022

Bridge of Weir, Scotland

- Developed efficient scheduling and reporting systems using Excel and PowerBi that resulted in cost savings of 280k p.a.
- Generated insightful efficiency reports for CEO's based on data analysis.
- Coordinated team tasks to ensure project deadlines were met.

Team Leader | Bridge Of Weir Leather

= 09 2017 - 12 2019

Bridge Of Weir, Scotland

- Conducted data analysis and reporting using advanced Excel functions and PowerBI, resulting in more informed decision making within the team.
- Successfully organized and delegated tasks, increasing team efficiency and productivity.

Production Technician | Bridge Of Weir Leather

i 08 2015 - 09 2017

Bridge Of Weir, Scotland

- Streamlined production workflow for maximum efficiency, saving valuable time and resources.
- Conducted regular quality checks to ensure consistent high standards of work output.
- Developed and implemented effective production strategies resulting in increased productivity and improved performance.
- Proactively identified and resolved potential issues in the production process to maintain smooth operations.

EDUCATION

Social Statistics | Szczecin University

2009 - 2012

Szczecin, Poland

• Bachelor's Degree in Applied Sociology (specialisation in statistics)

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Great passion for running. Completed two marathons and one ultra marathon.
- Horror movie fan.
- Really enjoy to read a lot of books